Bulkley Family Papers, 1803-1898 Ms B38
Fairfield Museum and History Center
Bulkley Family Papers, 1803-1898
Ms B38
Fairfield Museum and History Center
1.5 Linear feet 4 Boxes 2 oversize items 378 items
This collection contains items from several generations of the Bulkley and Perry families of Southport, CT.
Bulkley family
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical/Historical note
The Perrys and Bulkleys in this collection lived in Southport, CT. Walter Perry was born in 1770 and died in 1831. His children were: Gurdon (1807-1869), Elbert (1792-1820), and Oliver H. (1815-1882. Gurdon Perry's children were: Harriet, Helen (1826-1914) who married Edwin Bulkley, and Cornelius (1831-1889).
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of 4 boxes and 2 oversized items. Box I contains papers of the Bulkley family. Included are deeds, a guest book, family journal, maritime papers and probate papers. Box II contains papers of the Perry family. Included are letters and bills mostly to Gurdon Perry and his wife as well as Gurdon Perry's military papers. Box III contains account books of Gurdon Perry and Fanny B. Bulkley's cookbook. Box IV contains unidentified photo albums.
Oversize Item A is Gurdon Perry's account book. Oversize Item B contains an unidentified photo album.
Bulkley, Andrew; Bulkley, Edwin; Bulkley, Fannie B.; Perry, Cornelius; Perry, Elbert, 1792-1820; Perry, Gurdon, 1807-1869; Perry, Oliver H., 1815-1882; Perry, Walter, 1170-1831; Account books--Connecticut--Southport; Correspondence.; Deeds--Connecticut--Southport; Military orders; Probate records--Connecticut--Southport; Receipts(financial records); Ships; Southport(Conn.)
- Box I-Bulkley Papers, 71 items
  - Bulkley deeds, 1803-1879; Folder A; 10 items
    - Eleazer Bulkley from Joseph Squire, 1803
    - Eleazer Bulkley from Medad Gould, 1807
    - Andrew Bulkley from Eleazer Bulkley, 1815
    - Eleazer Bulkley from Joab Squire, 1815
    - Jonathan Bulkley from Joshua Jennings, 1816
    - Andrew Bulkley from Samuel Sturges, 1823
    - Andrew Bulkley from Eleazer Bulkley, et. al., 1841
    - Andrew Bulkley from Frederic Dimon, 1841
    - Edwin Bulkley from Lewis D. Bulkley, et al. (24 Old South Rd.), 1869
    - Edwin Bulkley from John Fennel, 1879
  - Deeds and documents re: Southport house, 1886-1936; Folder B; 10 items
  - Guest book of the Homestead--Theodora Bulkley, 1905-1924; Folder C; 1 item
  - Bills to Edwin Bulkley, 1848, 1851, 1854; Folder D; 24 items
  - Family journal, n.d.; Folder E; 1 item
  - Maritime papers, Folder F
    - Brig Moses Brown protest and declaration, 1837
    - Ship Lookout accounts, 1861, n.d.; 2 items
    - Brig Sterling trips, 1844
    - Letter to Messrs. E. Bulkley and son, 1831
    - Custom House account book, Fairfield, 1816, 1829; 1 item
  - Probate papers, wills, estate tax lists, Folder G
    - Andrew Bulkley, 1859, 1867; 4 items
    - Edwin Bulkley, 1874; 1 item
    - Ellen Sherwood, 1887; 1 item
    - Edwin Bulkley, 1898; 1 item
    - Helen P. Bulkley, 1898; 1 item
    - Jonathan Bulkley, 1898; 1 item
- Box II-Perry Papers, 300 items
  - Letters to Gurdon Perry, 1839-1849; Folder A; 15 items
    - Oliver Henry Perry, 1839, 1841; 4 items
    - Cornelius Perry, 1844; 2 items
    - Neptune Insurance Company, 1841-1842; 3 items
    - J. H. Cook, 1842
    - Henry Jones, 1846
    - Jon W. Lawrence, 1847
    - Connecticut Bank, 1849
    - Roberts & Sweetland re: flagstone walk #80 Harbor Rd.), 1849; 2 items
  - Letters to Gurdon Perry, 1853-1869; Folder B; 13 items
    - Cornelius Perry, 1858, 1861; 6 items
    - Various banks, 1853-1869; 6 items
    - Lyman Hunt, 1853
  - Letters to Gurdon Perry re: house sale, 1856-1857; Folder C; 9 items
  - Bills to Gurdon Perry, 1846-1848, 1863, 1896; Folder D; 9 items
  - Bills to Mrs. Gurdon Perry, 1872-1882; Folder E; 28 items
  - Bills to Mrs. Gurdon Perry, 1883-1888; Folder F; 40 items
  - Gurdon Perry Papers, Folder G
    - House expenses (780 Harbor Rd., Southport), 1848, 1853; 2 items
    - List book, 1832-1866
  - Gurdon Perry military papers, 1828-1839; Folder H
  - Cornelius Perry school papers, 1844, 1846; Folder I; 7 items
  - Miscellaneous letters sent to, Folder J
    - Captain Andrew Bulkley
    - Moses Bulkley, 1888
    - Mrs. Miranda Bulkley, 1812, 1815; 2 items
    - Mr. Jennings, 1845; 2 items
    - Mrs. A. S. Perry, 1856
    - Miss Helen Perry, 1844
    - Mrs. Gurdon Perry, n.d.; 3 items
    - Mr. Walter Perry, 1814. n.d.; 2 items
  - Miscellaneous papers, Folder K; 11 items
- Box III, 6 items
  - Gurdon Perry expense and account books, 1810-1832; Folder A; 3 items
  - Gurdon Perry estate inventory and will, 1869; Folder B; 2 items
  - Perry acount book, 1831-1869; Folder C
  - Fanny B. Bulkley cookbook, 1904; Folder D
- Box IV-Unidentified photo albums, 2 items
- Oversize Item A-Gurdon Perry account book
- Oversize Item B-Unidentified photo album